# Nikolai Dorofeev

# Fullstack Developer

IT specialist with experience in a wide range of technologies, focusing on Node.js ecosystem. Created web-applications from database and server layers to dynamic Single Page Applications and deployment to hosting.

⊕ d0rich.me ☑ dorich2000@gmail.com ♠ d0rich ☐ linkedin.com/in/d0rich t.me/d0rich

• Tbilisi, Georgia

## Work Experience

#### Full-stack Developer Exactpro (Georgia)

Jul 2022 - Present (1 year 5 months)

- Led development of an easy-to-deploy and easy-to-update docs web toolkit package based on Nuxt.js and Tailwind CSS.
- Contributed to 50+ Vue.js components.
- Integrated applications with 3+ 3rd party solutions such as GitHub or Algolia using REST API.
- Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements.
- Developed #1 architecture for providing traceability of digital assets between blockchains for Swift Hackathon 2022.
- Configured 10+ CI/CD pipelines for publishing static websites and npm packages via GitHub actions, GitLab CI.
- Mentored junior specialists and technical writers.

#### Full-stack Developer Exactpro

Jul 2021 - Jul 2022 (1 year 1 month)

- Developed a custom documentation portal with 7+ features for technical writers using Gridsome (Vue.js + GraphQL).
- Integrated applications with 3+ 3rd party solutions such as GitHub or Algolia.
- Analyzed 30+ user requirements to derive technical software design and performance requirements.
- Developed 10+ demonstration Python and Kotlin modules for th2 complex Kubernetes-based microservices framework with gRPC and RabbitMQ communication.
- Wrote 30+ clear and easy-to-understand documentation pages for complex Kubernetes-based - microservices framework.
- Configured 10+ CI/CD pipelines for building and publishing static websites via GitHub actions and Jenkins.

# **Projects**

- <u>d0rich design system</u>: 🎨 Design system inspired by Persona 5 UI
- <u>tradeb0t</u>: in Trading software with high integration possibilities
- th2-cli: The contraction of th
- <u>tweetst0rm</u>: 🐔 Simple app that uses GPT-3 for generating tweets.

#### Languages

- English: Upper-Intermediate
- Russian: Native

#### Skills



Database Design

# Certificates

- Enterprise Patterns (<u>foxminded.ua</u>, May 2023): <u>Course Page</u>,
   Certificate, Verify Certificate
- Architecting With Google Kubernetes Engine (<u>Coursera</u>, Oct 2021):
   Certificate
- Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing (<u>Google Digital Garage</u>, Jul 2021):
   Certificate

### Education

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Systems and Technologies in Business <u>Tomsk Polytechnic University</u>

Sep 2018 - Jul 2022 (3 years 11 months)

This program is aimed at training specialists in the field of information systems and technologies in business, who are able to solve problems of business management and economic activity using modern information technologies and systems. Projects were related to the development of e-commerce systems and integration with ERP systems.

Main learning stack: ASP.NET + MS SQL.

However, students was free to choose any technology stack for their projects.

Used technologies: Node.js, Python Flask, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Docker, etc.

Diploma project: distributed full-stack framework for trading automation implemented with Node.js and Vue.js.